Barcelona - contacto@danieldev.es - danieldev.es

Fullstack web developer

"I started with programming when I was about 13. At the moment, I have many years of experience and especially in Web Development, fullstack level. I've worked with backend, frontend, databases, deployments, services, apis, Linux management, etc. I've also been a person responsible for digital products and SEO"

Professional Experience

Panaworld S.L (2009 – 2018) ~9 years

A startup that runs the Internet Business since 2006. I worked with them when they held power in a good niche, the Browser video games. I took care of the web services and worked on SEO. I worked for them until a recession in that business niche.

- → FullStack Developer, Product Owner & SEO (2013 2018)

 After another promotion I was responsible of my FullStack Web developer position but also responsible for the product requirements. Managing the technical side and also other fields like content which was related to SEO. I was algo in charge of the SEO issues, analyzing what we did wrong and what not, looking after competitors, think about product improvements and features, run A/B designs for UX, building MVP's with new features and report to our CEO. As a programmer, I also had time to build some mobile games using UnityEngine and C# which were required to improve the services
- → FullStack Web Developer (2010 2013)
 After a promotion, my responsabilities were d

After a promotion, my responsabilities were design, program, and maintain code using PHP as backend and JS as frontend. Create and maintain a custom MVC based framework we made with PHP which was a core for our business. Use Javascript, Jquery, CSS, Bootstrap, Less, Ajax, etc. Create mobile first responsive layouts. Design, create and maintain MySQL databases. Create API services. Manage Linux Dedicated Servers and services like nginx. Pretty much all the typical tasks for a Fullstack web dev position.

→ Junior Frontend Web Developer (2009 – 2010)
Initially, my responsabilities were typing HTML code to make the designs alive with the aid of CSS, also typing small javascript code snippets or jQuery when required.

Cerámicas Montgatina S.L (2007 – 2008) ~2 years A ceramics factory where I used heavy pressure machinery and ABB robots in order to build high cuisine dishes. I left the job in order to start my career as a software developer.

→ **Robot ABB** Machinist (2007 – 2008)

Configuration, programming, starting up the machines, dealing with ABB Robots, assemble and dissasemble pressure molds, dealing with machines, changing valves, etc.

Ball Corporation / Aerocan (2004 – 2007) ~3 years

An International factory that built aluminium canisters like bottles, cans of spray, etc. I worked there until they moved the factory to another country.

→ Production and Quality Assurance (2004 – 2007)

Responsible for packaging and Quality assurance of the product that the machines built. Looking for issues, running small checks in the lab, and ocasionally moving stuff around our warehouse.

Cap de Creus vidres i aluminis S.L (2002 – 2003) ~1 year A medium-small company that built aluminium doors, windows and all sort of things related. This was my first official job because I've also helped my parents before before I was 18. I left the job because me and my father had to move to another City.

→ Manufacturer and assembler (2002 – 2003)

Measuring and cutting Technal aluminium bars, assembling accessories, basically creating windows or doors from bare aluminium material. Sometimes, also assembling in client places.

Education

- FP-2 DAW Spanish HNC UK equivalent about Web App Development (ongoing)
- ◆ Bachillerato Spanish GCE UK equivalent
- ◆ FP-1 electronics Spanish VET UK equivalent (incomplete)
- ◆ E.S.O Spanish GCSE UK equivalent

LANGUAGES

English Catalan Spanish

Professional Proficiency
Native
Native

IT Skills

| PHP | Javascript | MySQL |
|------------|------------|----------|
| HTML5 | CSS | Nodejs |
| C# | jQuery | Unity |
| Bootstrap | Linux | Git |
| Subversion | ReactJS | GatsbyJS |
| SEO | MediaQuery | Laravel |

Check out all my skills on my website danieldev.es/en/skills/

Digital projects I've made danieldev.es/en/projects/

My LinkedIn profile linkedin.com/in/daniel-developer-seo/

Contact Email contacto@danieldev.es

